[
    {
        "question": "He rejects charges that he was partly responsible for the \u2018casino atmosphere\u2019 that gripped US corporate life in the early 1980s.",
        "answer": "gripped"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a takeover campaign that has already seen vitriolic language, he responds to the charge that he is mounting the bid to enrich himself and his friends by saying: \u2018Nobody could take that as a criticism \u2014 this is an investor group.",
        "answer": "mounting"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sir: If Labour is to suggest the setting up of a specialist labour court (30 September), then such a momentous change in the industrial relations system deserves more discussion, and needs to be taken out of the hot-house of Labour Party conference politics.",
        "answer": "hot-house"
    },
    {
        "question": "Second, it would ensure that workers enjoyed positive rights under law and reduce the emphasis of union immunities.",
        "answer": "immunities"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now, it would appear from this article, that this ideal is shattered and a two-tiered Europe is on the cards.",
        "answer": "-tiered"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a man whom Rebecca West, a contemporary Balkan observer, called \u2018repulsive\u2019 and \u2018treacherous\u2019 for deserting his Serbian son-in-law, King Alexander, in the First World War, it is a sepia-tinted view of history.",
        "answer": "repulsive"
    },
    {
        "question": "These influences laid the foundations for the blend of the naive and the sophisticated which is the hallmark of Thomson's maturity.",
        "answer": "hallmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "He started by writing occasional articles but in 1939 he wrote The State of Music, a trenchant and provocative assessment of the machinery of the musical profession at the time.",
        "answer": "machinery"
    },
    {
        "question": "He seemed a genial and indestructible landmark in the history of American music, in spite of defective hearing which had bothered him since the late Seventies.",
        "answer": "landmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "But while the DTI would override the Treasury, a new \u2018powerful Department of Consumer Affairs\u2019 would antagonise the DTI.",
        "answer": "antagonise"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mr Cook argued that 10 years of Thatcherism had been forced on most people, who had never voted Conservative, and that many of those who opposed PR in the Labour Party wanted to use the same undemocratic power \u2018to ram socialism down the throats of a majority who didn't vote for it\u2019.",
        "answer": "throats"
    },
    {
        "question": "WHO TO WATCH While the best that chart music can manage in the way of band names is Black Box, the pub circuit has always been ripe with imaginative handles.",
        "answer": "handles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Half Moon Putney 93 Lower Richmond Rd, SW15 (788 2387) Better known for its jazz, but a good, wholesome venue for rock nonetheless.",
        "answer": "wholesome"
    },
    {
        "question": "But people seem to think that stories are written to a prescription, that you sit down and say, you don't want it to be sexist, you don't want it to be racist.",
        "answer": "prescription"
    },
    {
        "question": "Despite Mr Dobbs's tireless efforts, this is another revolution which Britain is likely to be viewing from the sidelines.",
        "answer": "tireless"
    },
    {
        "question": "It was a magnificent fightback and such was Welsh distress that they never looked like preventing it.",
        "answer": "distress"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why, though, could these supposed championship contenders not have tried to emulate the fine passing that had sprinkled the previous weekend's Merseyside joust?",
        "answer": "joust"
    },
    {
        "question": "They ought to have pocketed three points in the first half-hour but Tony Adams, a more threatening centre-forward on his forays than the current Alan Smith, missed the target with two headers and David Rocastle let Dave Beasant save a penalty, much as the stretch-version keeper had done for Wimbledon in the 1988 FA Cup final.",
        "answer": "pocketed"
    },
    {
        "question": "The specific role of bishops which is to be exercised in communion with the see of Peter in ensuring the unity and continuity of the faith is vital if we are to hand on the faith of Peter, Gregory and Augustine.",
        "answer": "communion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Plus a backdrop of houses covering the valley walls on either side, a reminder that wherever industrialised societies decide to deal with their most intractable problems, they are unlikely to find a place to do so which is not in somebody's back yard.",
        "answer": "intractable"
    },
    {
        "question": "The TV western seemed to fade into the sunset some time in the mid-1970s, victim of a narcissistic age that preferred to look at prosperous, smart-alecky or violent images of itself (Dallas, Cheers, Miami Vice).",
        "answer": "narcissistic"
    },
    {
        "question": "It was the only new drama series in US network TV to be allowed a second series this year, despite a relatively lowly 49th ranking in the ratings.",
        "answer": "lowly"
    },
    {
        "question": "You can sue the solicitor for what you would have collected, had he done his job properly, because the law reckons he owed you, as well as his client, a duty of care.",
        "answer": "reckons"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the vaporous presences that float through this slender and anaemic first novel by a notable poet would appear to support the claim.",
        "answer": "anaemic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Andrew Motion presents us with here is a static and humourless mood-piece filled with over-elaborate imagery.",
        "answer": "presents"
    },
    {
        "question": "This violent event, described at length in hysterically colourful terms, is the only piece of history to be woven convincingly into the plot.",
        "answer": "woven"
    },
    {
        "question": "One moment an avenue of chestnut trees looks \u2018like a child's drawing of ghosts\u2019; the next it appears \u2018frightening but derelict, like extinguished chandeliers\u2019; and finally the chestnuts \u2018prance at him, holding up their gleaming branches like hysterics.\u2019",
        "answer": "prance"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 1985 Lancia Y10 (lead only) sells for around \u00a32,000 whereas the similar Fiat Uno 55 from the same year, converted to run on unleaded, is worth around \u00a3500 more.",
        "answer": "converted"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find a 1980 Toyota Corolla or 1982 Nissan Sunny that has not succumbed to rust, and you can buy with confidence.",
        "answer": "succumbed"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the \u2018greenness\u2019 of going unleaded still seems a bit of a grey area, it is possible to switch to diesel without a shadow of environmental doubt.",
        "answer": "greenness"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prestige comes in the shape of a Mercedes with the 240D or \u2018Stuttgart Taxi\u2019, commanding \u00a37,000 but returning unfailing reliability.",
        "answer": "commanding"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sales combine items of charm at fairly accessible prices with some rare treasures aimed at big-time collectors.",
        "answer": "charm"
    },
    {
        "question": "Drink: Desire in search of a name: Do the French have the \u2018mot juste\u2019 to describe the desire for a reviving drink?",
        "answer": "reviving"
    },
    {
        "question": "Are they quenching?",
        "answer": "quenching"
    },
    {
        "question": "The summer's sprawl begins to be oppressive at this stage in the year and trigger fingers are itching to snip back overgrown mallows, clear out the mildewing foliage of golden rod and reduce the overpowering bulk of bullyboy ground cover.",
        "answer": "sprawl"
    },
    {
        "question": "The summer's sprawl begins to be oppressive at this stage in the year and trigger fingers are itching to snip back overgrown mallows, clear out the mildewing foliage of golden rod and reduce the overpowering bulk of bullyboy ground cover.",
        "answer": "bullyboy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Summer bedding is looking tired and should be removed so that the ground can be cleaned and fed ready for spring bulbs or wallflowers.",
        "answer": "bedding"
    },
    {
        "question": "They held up the bright new diesel buses and, even worse, blocked the progress of private motorists in bulbous Austins and lumpen Humbers in canyon-like city thoroughfares.",
        "answer": "bright"
    },
    {
        "question": "After all, Mancunians and visitors to the Manchester conurbation are going to have to look at these mechanical millipedes for well into the twenty-first century.",
        "answer": "millipedes"
    },
    {
        "question": "FROM the top of the dome of St Paul's Cathedral the view is no longer dominated by City church steeples but by an intrusive cacophony of drab, characterless Sixties boxes.",
        "answer": "cacophony"
    },
    {
        "question": "Scott was so pleased with the style he had evolved at Battersea, a treatment that humanised industrial forms without denying their function, that he also used it on the Guinness Factory at Park Royal, west London.",
        "answer": "humanised"
    },
    {
        "question": "Buddy invites us to regard Holly in the same light, mocking (in a horribly nudging re-creation) Lubbock old-timers like The Hayriders, who sing: \u2018When the sun goes down on Blue Ridge Mountain It's the time to whistle in your ear.\u2019",
        "answer": "nudging"
    },
    {
        "question": "The voice of rock'n'roll, in contrast, is almost unrelievedly soupy.",
        "answer": "soupy"
    },
    {
        "question": "That, after all, is what Don McLean did so brilliantly in \u2018American Pie\u2019, a personal reaction to \u2018the day the music died\u2019.",
        "answer": "brilliantly"
    },
    {
        "question": "Almost every year has witnessed the discovery of new artistic terrain \u2014 graffiti art, Soviet art, Australian art, the art of Latin America.",
        "answer": "terrain"
    },
    {
        "question": "The enormous rise in the economic value of her work has developed in tandem with the increased critical and popular response to her particular blend of naive style and incisive content.",
        "answer": "tandem"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the mask fall: Does not the ritual repetition of those familiar features \u2018mask\u2019 far more than it uncovers?",
        "answer": "mask"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hale's eyes stare knowingly at the viewer, a human sacrifice to an alienated and consumerist culture.",
        "answer": "alienated"
    },
    {
        "question": "The horizontality of her fallen body is juxtaposed to the vertical thrust of the apartment building.",
        "answer": "thrust"
    },
    {
        "question": "At its most simple, La Chingada, as the mother of Mestizo culture is \u2018the Mother forcibly opened, violated or deceived\u2019.",
        "answer": "violated"
    },
    {
        "question": "The inter-relationship of body and dress so self-consciously referred to in many of Kahlo's most polemical works (Fig. 12) has been strangely inverted by her current popularity.",
        "answer": "polemical"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the more economically puny ASEAN countries (Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore, Brunei, Thailand and the Philippines) were to bury their reservations, then the high growth from other partners, including such tigers as Thailand and South Korea alongside the more mature economies of Japan and Australia, could mean a dynamic coalition.",
        "answer": "dynamic"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a desperately competitive climate, where anyone bright and competent could go down the road and pick up a better paid job with kinder hours and more congenial working conditions from someone like British Telecom, the railways ran a service dependent on people who belonged to a narrow and inbred working culture, with outdated procedures of training and promotion, and an institutional reliance on overtime working, whose wholly disgraceful dimensions are symbolised by the fact that maximum weekly hours were only recently cut to 72 hours a week.",
        "answer": "dimensions"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is sad, and somewhat ominous, that so little of that should have been reflected in the sombre statement which Mr Parkinson made in the House yesterday..",
        "answer": "sombre"
    },
    {
        "question": "Outside the capital, accident and emergency services were being provided in most areas, but the ban on emergency work was tightened.",
        "answer": "tightened"
    },
    {
        "question": "There are three key causes of the shambles: Mr Kenneth Clarke; the failure to separate emergency from non-emergency work; and the Whitley Council negotiating machinery.",
        "answer": "machinery"
    },
    {
        "question": "But \u2018posturing and pretending\u2019 went far beyond the unions.",
        "answer": "posturing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mr Justice Hutchison said the 1936 Act primarily envisages a system where the local authority has a power and a duty to try to secure that premises are not in a state which constitutes a statutory nuisance.",
        "answer": "envisages"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an ideal world, there would be no need for either, but for now I would rather see the frustration expressed in these light-hearted >terms than in the sort of man-hating bitterness that has given feminism such a bad name.",
        "answer": "light-hearted"
    },
    {
        "question": "Despite many and varied flurries of activity in the first 40 minutes, Arsenal seemed reasonably secure if not inspired.",
        "answer": "flurries"
    },
    {
        "question": "They held their line and competed hard in midfield, damping down Oldham's initial verve and preparing themselves for more of the same in the second half.",
        "answer": "damping"
    },
    {
        "question": "He finds out what the needs of the business are, and prescribes the cure.",
        "answer": "prescribes"
    },
    {
        "question": "The analyst is then forced on the defensive, explaining why new features can not be included because they are technically difficult or prohibitively expensive.",
        "answer": "prohibitively"
    },
    {
        "question": "First, a comprehensive civil disobedience campaign was begun by which people severed, or minimised, all the contact points by which they were bound to the Israeli occupation authority.",
        "answer": "severed"
    },
    {
        "question": "The structure of the developing national authority has been both diffuse enough to prevent it from being destroyed by any one single sweep of arrests (there have been more than 50,000 arrests since the Intifada's outbreak), and coherent enough to allow for the existence of a unified resistance strategy.",
        "answer": "destroyed"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high level of mobility in the structure allows for continuous interchange of roles and ideas, and retains for the Unified National Command the closeness to grass roots that is required to make it truly reflect people's wishes and sentiments.",
        "answer": "closeness"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thrusts of resistance (mass demonstrations, resignations, tax rebellions, etc) would come in crests.",
        "answer": "Thrusts"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Intifada is the midwife of freedom.",
        "answer": "midwife"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Way you go, Patty,\u2019 he said softly, and the dog was off, hurling herself along the embankment, all paws and flying ears, after a rabbit who had been sitting in a patch of sun but disappeared with contemptuous ease as she came close.",
        "answer": "hurling"
    },
    {
        "question": "He watched his aunt and Miss Williams wordlessly consult each other, but knew his aunt would do as she was told; successful solicitor though she was, she was ten years younger than Miss Williams and, as she complained, totally intimidated by her as she had not been by anyone since her late headmistress.",
        "answer": "solicitor"
    },
    {
        "question": "The CID sergeant thanked her gravely and went to stand beside Jamie who was peering down the embankment, looking pinched.",
        "answer": "sergeant"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018A few days,\u2019 the sergeant said, grimly.",
        "answer": "sergeant"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Angela Morgan, at least two major clients were in danger of not getting the assiduous service they were paying for, and it would be well worth trying to see if one of them, whom he knew to be a fellow refugee from family life at the weekends, could be found.",
        "answer": "assiduous"
    },
    {
        "question": "He had to admit that this particular client hardly added to the general decorative smartness of the place.",
        "answer": "smartness"
    },
    {
        "question": "Peter Yeo, who had known this particular juggernaut since he had his first small factory and two stores and dirt under his fingernails from shifting packing-cases personally, was not fazed by the question.",
        "answer": "juggernaut"
    },
    {
        "question": "Penelope, however, it had to be acknowledged, had made no attempt to rise above the blow she had been dealt by finding a dazzling girl of her own age favoured over herself in her uncle's will.",
        "answer": "dazzling"
    },
    {
        "question": "Penelope glared at her, turning an ungraceful scarlet, but Mrs Huntley held her ground.",
        "answer": "ungraceful"
    },
    {
        "question": "Her husband Francis had made a slightly better showing than her daughter Jennifer, who was looking particularly ragged.",
        "answer": "ragged"
    },
    {
        "question": "The man, a stocky, greying fifty-year-old in a navy raincoat over a suit, his hair cut short, was attended by a uniformed policewoman, hair smartly set under the cap, her eyes watchful in the wide, flat, placid face, and both of them were standing square and stolid.",
        "answer": "smartly"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Paul Jones and the emotional somersaults when the music stopped and they came face to face for the very first time.",
        "answer": "somersaults"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whether the life sentence is regarded as a sufficient denunciation in society depends on the public's perception of what life imprisonment means: if it is widely believed that it results in an average of nine years' imprisonment, the effect will be somewhat blunted.",
        "answer": "blunted"
    },
    {
        "question": "Intent to kill may be regarded as the most obvious and indisputable form of fault element for murder, but to some extent that depends on the meaning of \u2018intent\u2019.",
        "answer": "element"
    },
    {
        "question": "The House of Lords upheld D's conviction for murder: an intent to cause really serious injury is sufficient for murder, without any proof that the defendant intended, or even contemplated, the possibility that death would result.",
        "answer": "contemplated"
    },
    {
        "question": "That jarring manifestation of furious technology seemed as remote and ridiculous as a dream, as silence settled down on Kielderhead and the hawk's whistle came down from the moors.",
        "answer": "jarring"
    },
    {
        "question": "That jarring manifestation of furious technology seemed as remote and ridiculous as a dream, as silence settled down on Kielderhead and the hawk's whistle came down from the moors.",
        "answer": "remote"
    },
    {
        "question": "Water is everywhere: canals, streams, small busy rivers with charming names like the Boutonne, the Mignon and the Belle, and big lazy rivers like the Sevre Niortaise and the Charente.",
        "answer": "lazy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wriggling across country on the D216 to Port-d'Envaux, you come to two more chateaux: 18th-century Panloy, flaking romantically away on its hillock overlooking a bend in the Charente and, almost next door, the much older, moated Crazannes, half-smothered in amazing flamboyant Gothic carving.",
        "answer": "smothered"
    },
    {
        "question": "But these themes are always interspersed with more fanciful ones: grimacing masks, weird animals, exuberant abstract patterns.",
        "answer": "exuberant"
    },
    {
        "question": "The masts may seem unsightly to those unused to them, but I am sure it is simply a matter of getting accustomed.",
        "answer": "masts"
    },
    {
        "question": "Political consciousness is low on the Meadowell Estate.",
        "answer": "consciousness"
    },
    {
        "question": "MP Neville Trotter is a pear-shaped Tory with pear-shaped vowels who has little appeal to the people of Meadowell, and a dwindling appeal in the middle-class suburbs where unemployment is also climbing.",
        "answer": "pear-shaped"
    },
    {
        "question": "There were also some lines intended for local consumption: \u2018Higher petrol prices from the Liberal Democrats \u2026 that's not gon na help a rural area \u2026",
        "answer": "consumption"
    },
    {
        "question": "More to the point, it was Bagehot who said: \u2018A constitutional statesman is in general a man of common opinions and uncommon abilities.\u2019",
        "answer": "constitutional"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mr Goodson, who became interested in the sonar capacity of dolphins after hearing one while swimming off the Welsh coast, has experimented with various shapes of sound reflectors.",
        "answer": "reflectors"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Moray Firth, they placed a \u2018headline barrier\u2019, from which they had suspended reflectors at two-metre intervals.",
        "answer": "reflectors"
    },
    {
        "question": "LA MAMA ETC \u2014 for \u2018Experimental Theatre Company\u2019 \u2014 is a tiny cauldron of a theatre on the Lower East Side, the creation of the extraordinary Ellen Stewart.",
        "answer": "cauldron"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is not that prospects for earnings are 10 p.c. better that they were in the middle of last week, but it is possible to argue that prospects are that much better than they would have been under a Labour government and that the market was discounting such a result.",
        "answer": "prospects"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an earlier than expected Commercial Court judgment, Mr Justice Saville found that the members had not produced enough evidence of irregularities in the \u2018LMX spiral\u2019, which sends catastrophe risks swirling round the market to stop the usual process of calling on cash deposits to make good syndicate losses.",
        "answer": "spiral"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most animals today do seem to have bodies that accord well with the functions they have to carry out to survive: flyers are aerodynamically efficient, active swimmers have suitable streamlining, herbivorous mammals have teeth appropriate for grinding plant food, and so on.",
        "answer": "swimmers"
    },
    {
        "question": "The outline of the soft parts are also clearly displayed, so that the animal has been preserved almost in frozen motion.",
        "answer": "frozen"
    },
    {
        "question": "Canals within the algae stand out as rods in this kind of preservation, which is common in Ordovician rocks.",
        "answer": "Canals"
    },
    {
        "question": "This species has a finely toothed margin; a large, wide leaf born on a long stem.",
        "answer": "toothed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Protagonists of the warm-blooded theory will show some of the horned dinosaurs charging over the Cretaceous plains like furious reptilian rhinoceroses!",
        "answer": "Protagonists"
    },
    {
        "question": "Meanwhile bad housing, bad sanitation, lack of education, and other perennial ills associated with overcrowding and poverty have been routinely denounced by political leaders and social reformers.",
        "answer": "perennial"
    },
    {
        "question": "Or would a simple injection of resources transform Kafkaesque honeycombs into happy living-spaces, with a consequent decline in inner-city ills?",
        "answer": "honeycombs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Urban Programme consisted of grants and initiatives under the 1969 Local Government Grants (Social Need) Act, which was intended as a flexible instrument to provide supplementary help to local authorities in the fields of housing, education, and health.",
        "answer": "fields"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the most bizarre aspects of government policy has been the effective murder of the voluntary sector, and its appropriation, by subterfuge, into the Tory version of the corporate state.",
        "answer": "appropriation"
    },
    {
        "question": "However, the later withdrawal of government support, with the scrapping of the Community Programme as unemployment receded, left many of these voluntary organizations high and dry.",
        "answer": "receded"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018scourge of criminal violence\u2019 was, Whitelaw argued, a danger to the whole framework of consent and legality on which the political institutions of British society were based.",
        "answer": "scourge"
    },
    {
        "question": "In reply Roy Hattersley supported the call for the immediate suppression of street violence, but warned that the roots of such riots could not be dealt with until all people felt they had a stake in British society (ibid.: cols. 1407\u20139)",
        "answer": "suppression"
    },
    {
        "question": "During 1985 this issue was raised once again, though by then the extent of mass unemployment and urban de-industrialization and decay was more stark than it had been in 198l.",
        "answer": "stark"
    },
    {
        "question": "Responding to the Handsworth events Douglas Hurd was moved to argue forcibly that such events were senseless and reflected more on those who participated in them than on the society in which they took place: \u2018The sound which law abiding people in Handsworth heard on Monday night, the echoes of which I picked up on Tuesday, was not a cry for help but a cry for loot\u2019 (Financial Times, 13 September 1985).",
        "answer": "echoes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Responding to the Handsworth events Douglas Hurd was moved to argue forcibly that such events were senseless and reflected more on those who participated in them than on the society in which they took place: \u2018The sound which law abiding people in Handsworth heard on Monday night, the echoes of which I picked up on Tuesday, was not a cry for help but a cry for loot\u2019 (Financial Times, 13 September 1985).",
        "answer": "loot"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus were explained anatomically the enormous jaws, high cheek bones, prominent superciliary arches, solitary lines on the palms, extreme size of the orbits, handle-shaped or sessile ears found in criminals, savages and apes, insensibility of pain, extremely acute sight, tattooing, excessive idleness, love of orgies and the craving for evil for its own sake \u2026",
        "answer": "sessile"
    },
    {
        "question": "The majority of offenders do not come from disturbed or broken homes, and many broken homes do not produce delinquents.",
        "answer": "disturbed"
    },
    {
        "question": "The problem with assessing the influence of parental and family dimensions, such as weak supervision or parental criminality, is the fact that they are closely linked to various aspects of social and economic disadvantage, such as poverty, overcrowding and poor housing.",
        "answer": "assessing"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the UK we seem to be lagging well behind the USA in the construction of databases on hazardous sites and especially hazard events such as those involving toxic releases.",
        "answer": "lagging"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the transformation of a leggy young filly into a sleekly beautiful racehorse had been her doing.",
        "answer": "racehorse"
    },
    {
        "question": "Madame Mattli might be a stickler for detail, with a generous helping of the artistic temperament which kept her tight-coiled as a spring and which would explode into frenzy if the smallest detail was not as it should be, but she also had a kind face and deep perceptive eyes.",
        "answer": "tight-coiled"
    },
    {
        "question": "Paula's stomach turned a somersault.",
        "answer": "somersault"
    },
    {
        "question": "Paula perched herself against the cutting table trying to look nonchalant.",
        "answer": "perched"
    },
    {
        "question": "Her smile spread.",
        "answer": "spread"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the stroboscopic view, the giant pistons were the only things moving \u2014 until a figure detached itself from the wall, its grey colour exactly that of the background steel.",
        "answer": "stroboscopic"
    },
    {
        "question": "The curtain was a dense, opaque greenish-yellow, and something was right behind it, a shape pressing against the humped plastic standing there looking down at him, half seen, half imagined.",
        "answer": "humped"
    },
    {
        "question": "To his right the ground rose gently towards the southern cliffs and he could see the dark mouth of a concrete pillbox, undemolished since the war, and as seemingly indestructible as the great hulks of wave-battered concrete, remnants of the old fortifications which lay half-submerged in the sand along part of the beach.",
        "answer": "pillbox"
    },
    {
        "question": "To the north the broken arches and stumps of the ruined Benedictine abbey gleamed golden in the afternoon sun against the crinkled blue of the sea and, breasting a small ridge, he glimpsed for the first time the topsail of Larksoken Mill and beyond it, against the skyline, the great grey bulk of Larksoken Nuclear power Station.",
        "answer": "golden"
    },
    {
        "question": "The headland was empty and almost bare, the few straggling trees, distorted by the wind, struggled to keep their precarious hold in the uncompromising soil.",
        "answer": "uncompromising"
    },
    {
        "question": "And now he was passing a second and more dilapidated pillbox and it struck him that the whole headland had the desolate look of an old battlefield, the corpses long since carted away but the air vibrating still with the gunfire of long-lost battles, while the power station loomed over it like a grandiose modern monument to the unknown dead.",
        "answer": "desolate"
    },
    {
        "question": "Was it the faint smell of herbs and newly baked dough, the soft ticking of the wall-mounted clock which seemed both to mark the passing seconds and yet to hold time in thrall, the rhythmic moaning of the sea through the half-open door, the sense of well-fed ease conveyed by the two cushioned armchairs, the open hearth?",
        "answer": "well-fed"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an impulse he reversed the Jaguar and drove quickly back to Martyr's Cottage.",
        "answer": "impulse"
    },
    {
        "question": "There was a bar beneath which the child's rigid legs were obstinately stuck.",
        "answer": "obstinately"
    },
    {
        "question": "This boat was called Dream Baby, and she was clearly an expensive infant for rods and whip-aerials and outriggers splayed from her upperworks like the antennae of some outlandish insect.",
        "answer": "whip-"
    },
    {
        "question": "I was calling Sweetman's bluff, confident he would not dare pull the trigger, and equally confident that my marine training would let me turn him into mincemeat.",
        "answer": "mincemeat"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sounds are the same as those of daylight, yet somehow the night magnifies and sharpens the creak of a yielding block, the sigh of air over a shroud, the stretching of a sail, the hiss of water sliding sleek against the hull, the curl of a quarter-wave falling away, and the thump as a wave strikes the cutwater to be sheared into two bright slices of whiteness.",
        "answer": "slices"
    },
    {
        "question": "I wished that Ellen and Rickie would go to their beds, for the soft mutter of their voices was an intrusion on the dark and star-studded infinity through which I steered Wavebreaker.",
        "answer": "intrusion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lewis got up and pulled the curtains across with a pettish jerk of his hands.",
        "answer": "pettish"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018A bloody good thing or our childhood would have been a misery instead of just a bore.\u2019",
        "answer": "bloody"
    },
    {
        "question": "One thing about Zosie's pilfering, she never stole rubbish.",
        "answer": "rubbish"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adam closed the front door and stood there for a moment as if he could not wrench himself away.",
        "answer": "wrench"
    },
    {
        "question": "So much of its beauty had been stripped from it by the whipping winds.",
        "answer": "whipping"
    },
    {
        "question": "No golden light bathed the red brick of the house.",
        "answer": "bathed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Only thus, only by pretending unreality, pretending this was a part he acted, could he go on, cross the wild, shaggy grass, go past the black-branched cedar tree, arrive at the porch set in its four Doric columns and insert his key in the lock.",
        "answer": "shaggy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Key variables such as the quality of staff at any level and the current morale are only expressible in general verbal descriptive terms.",
        "answer": "expressible"
    },
    {
        "question": "This condition is known as foreclosure.",
        "answer": "foreclosure"
    },
    {
        "question": "The few girls who enter science will not usually show these foreclosure characteristics.",
        "answer": "foreclosure"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018detour, of Stalinism is thus formalized as Marxism's own descent into its unconscious, resulting in a dream-work of heterogeneous histories that have eluded systematization and subsumption into the single meaning of Marxism's own reading of history.",
        "answer": "dream-work"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sartre's account thus sets up the articulation of history, univocal meaning, and totality as the indissoluble set of elements required for the validation of Marxism, necessary in order to save it from its detour from itself.",
        "answer": "detour"
    },
    {
        "question": "Marxism is rigorously true if History is totalization; it is not so any more if human history decomposes into a plurality of particular histories, or if, in any case, within the relationship of immanence that characterizes struggle, the negation of each adversary by the other is on principle detotalizing.",
        "answer": "adversary"
    },
    {
        "question": "That means both that there is a dialectical meaning of the practical ensemble \u2026 and that each singular event totalizes in itself the practical ensemble in the infinite richness of its singularity\u2019 (II, 26).",
        "answer": "richness"
    },
    {
        "question": "In open battle and in the plundering expeditions that constituted the normal form of aggressive warfare, they needed the backing of archers, both mounted and on foot, and of numerous infantrymen.",
        "answer": "backing"
    },
    {
        "question": "The divergence was sharpened by the application of a theoretical distinction, the fruit of Augustinian theology, amplified as the century went on by canon and Roman law reference; princes pronounced their campaigns just wars (fought against aggressors with the aim of re-establishing peace) or public wars (declared by a competent authority in the public interest), while they condemned the wars of lesser men as infractions of the peace.",
        "answer": "fruit"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moral autonomy is concerned with individuals not with groups; a conception of autonomy which depends upon group membership displays its own contradiction.",
        "answer": "conception"
    },
    {
        "question": "The immature deliberative faculty will mature; children have the \u2018possibility apparent\u2019 of turning into rational beings (Hobbes); they love to be reated as though they were rational though they are not so yet (Locke); you can give the prerational child reasons for acting in certain ways and he will turn into the youth who is capable of having principles (Kant).",
        "answer": "immature"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tension between these theoretical views of children as non-rational, non-autonomous beings and the practical knowledge of real children is evident in those quotations from Hobbes and Locke and Kant and Mill.",
        "answer": "autonomous"
    },
    {
        "question": "But then, either Hobbes has failed to distinguish the child from at least the higher and domesticated animals or the force of \u2018intelligently\u2019 must be explained in such a way as to exclude animals.",
        "answer": "distinguish"
    },
    {
        "question": "Their problem seems to be not one of the inability to choose goals or to form strategies for achieving them, but an incorrigible propensity to choose the wrong ones and an awesome efficiency in achieving them unless adults intervene.",
        "answer": "incorrigible"
    },
    {
        "question": "A good many men came into the room by no means inclined to acquiesce in the proposed arrangement.",
        "answer": "arrangement"
    },
    {
        "question": "His strategy was rather to canalize the enthusiasm of the diehards into party channels, to articulate their views, and to create unity from the sense of movement.",
        "answer": "canalize"
    },
    {
        "question": "In parliament there would be a carefully organized campaign of resistance that would at least slow the government down and raise Unionist morale.",
        "answer": "campaign"
    },
    {
        "question": "I told Northcliffe that if his people would make enquiries at our Central Office, he would find that our nightly regiment of speakers was at least as well worth reporting as the Radical contingent, but that I realized that from the Press point of view, no doubt, our speakers did not play up to the reporters by> handing them their speeches in advance, and by other tricks of the kind to which the Radical orators have recourse.",
        "answer": "regiment"
    },
    {
        "question": "So in the supply of information to newspapers predisposed to support the party, much was achieved merely by employing a specialist.",
        "answer": "predisposed"
    },
    {
        "question": "The later history of the Daily Express suggests not: when the Express became hostile in the 1920s, Younger raged \" when I think of the large sum of money this office has put into that gutter print it makes my blood boil \".",
        "answer": "gutter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other organizations could not be absorbed but could still be brought within the Central Office orbit.",
        "answer": "absorbed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Since it is the equation [formula] that needs to be satisfied, we should choose the potential as a vector (called, not without logic, the vector potential), defined by the equation [formula].",
        "answer": "potential"
    },
    {
        "question": "Since it is the equation [formula] that needs to be satisfied, we should choose the potential as a vector (called, not without logic, the vector potential), defined by the equation [formula].",
        "answer": "potential"
    },
    {
        "question": "There is now cylindrical symmetry and a net charge per unit length [formula], yielding for the radial component of the electric field [formula].",
        "answer": "component"
    },
    {
        "question": "The electric force on an electron of charge e travelling at the edge of the beam (R = a) is it is in the radial direction pointing outwards.",
        "answer": "beam"
    },
    {
        "question": "He also kissed Frederica and introduced the woman, fumbling her name, as \" a colleague \" and Frederica as \" Frederica \u2014 you must forgive me, I never know what name you re working under, women these days are so protean. \"",
        "answer": "fumbling"
    },
    {
        "question": "\" You could read it another way, \" said Alexander, interested now, \" you could read the pears as androgynous in themselves, as partly male. \"",
        "answer": "androgynous"
    },
    {
        "question": "They were beginning to attract a penumbra of gallery-goers, as though they were offering a guided tour.",
        "answer": "penumbra"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sexless voices rose in the cold.",
        "answer": "sexless"
    },
    {
        "question": "The voices played with the slaughter of the innocents, treble and descant hunting each other, while she bowed her head, unable to sing in tune.",
        "answer": "slaughter"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Though in Van Gogh's case, the names, Theodorus, Vincent, Vincent, Theodorus, appeared and reappeared from generation to generation, the cultural parallels to certain persisting aspects of the family face, a heavy brow, an intense blue eye, a cheek bone, a nostril.)",
        "answer": "persisting"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nuns ascended and descended a cool grey stair in winged white caps.",
        "answer": "winged"
    },
    {
        "question": "Xavier Mellery, the painter of the nuns, was described in the catalogue as \" creating a light which is the negation of that which envelops our immediate visual experience of things; it is rather the Interior light of your mind \u2026 \"",
        "answer": "negation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clare still swapped one night a week off with Stephanie and reported subsequent events to Gilda, who now managed the shoe shop: occasionally she visited Clare for an evening meal.",
        "answer": "swapped"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018We've had more paperwork, not less, since the trust took over,\u2019 Buzz said tartly.",
        "answer": "tartly"
    },
    {
        "question": "So kindly curb your theatrical, James Bond streak.",
        "answer": "theatrical"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hell of a lot of difference really, it's surprising just a",
        "answer": "Hell"
    },
    {
        "question": "You're wheel-less are you?",
        "answer": "wheel-"
    },
    {
        "question": "We've only popped in to see whether you would like a lift into town now, before we go, rather than go into town and then come back just in case you want to",
        "answer": "popped"
    },
    {
        "question": "Erm it's a load of rubbish anyway!",
        "answer": "rubbish"
    },
    {
        "question": "Go and get nine tickets, or I start right up all the bloody year round for that.",
        "answer": "bloody"
    },
    {
        "question": "But I mean they were banging they were banging fifteen hundred in for that disco for the first",
        "answer": "banging"
    },
    {
        "question": "Exhausted.",
        "answer": "Exhausted"
    },
    {
        "question": "Yeah, she's only coming up for six weeks, mm, a monster.",
        "answer": "coming"
    },
    {
        "question": "So you got to do eighteen shared by six is three and eighteen",
        "answer": "shared"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lower Thornton That's actually gone, been reduced now to",
        "answer": "reduced"
    },
    {
        "question": "She won't of watched it, cos it's bound to be on a Wednesday night!",
        "answer": "bound"
    },
    {
        "question": "We could can prime them up on what to say and types of things to talk about so they don't get moaned down or something!",
        "answer": "prime"
    },
    {
        "question": "I know that, but will you make it stick.",
        "answer": "stick"
    },
    {
        "question": "Right on top of him and it turned round and smacked",
        "answer": "smacked"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hole in the head, ain't you?",
        "answer": "hole"
    },
    {
        "question": "It's a most it is not an international subject.",
        "answer": "subject"
    },
    {
        "question": "to be transplanted",
        "answer": "transplanted"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which arrangement?",
        "answer": "arrangement"
    },
    {
        "question": "I don't want to spend a fortnight on the road.",
        "answer": "spend"
    },
    {
        "question": "From place to the from another to the and backwards again",
        "answer": "backwards"
    }
]